JAMES RUTLEDGE

+1 512 423 8906 github.com/jmz527 **EMAIL** jarutledge2@gmail.com TWITTER twitter.com/jmz527 jamesaaronrutledge.com LINKEDIN linkedin.com/in/jmz527 **PERSONAL**

I am a TDD friendly, full-stack web developer with over five years of experience. I thrive on complexity & I believe the world deserves beautiful data structures. If you are looking for an untapped source of homegrown, raw potential with a reservoir of patience to boot, then I am your guy.

EXPERIENCE

September 2015 – Present

ENERGY METRICS

Software Developer | New York, NY

- Built Object-Oriented JavaScript widgets for front-end data manipulation.
- Created interactive graphs using Highcharts.
- Gained a great deal of proficiency with Twitter Bootstrap.

April 2015 – July 2015

GENERAL ASSEMBLY

Full-Stack Web Development Student | Austin, TX

- 13 week full-time intensive program on full-stack web development, product development, programming fundamentals, collaborative teamwork, & agile work-flow.
- TurnPlot, a social platform with a virtual grid, provides a digital space for users to cultivate their personal brands. Built using Ruby on Rails & PostgreSQL.
- PigMapper, a social analytics app allowing users to track their emotional well being, over time, using colors. Built with NodeJS &
- App-e-tite, a group project I lead, review app for restaurants, built using Ruby on Rails & PostgreSQL.

October 2010 -January 2013

MIND WINK

Co-Founder/Junior Web Developer | Austin, TX

- Designed & built websites/apps using Drupal, Wordpress & Bootstrap frameworks, gaining an in-depth understanding of front-end development practices.
- Managed Facebook & Twitter media feeds & tracked user base using the Facebook API.
- Lead pitch-meetings, developed presentations, established agile project management system & managed projects.
- Worked closely with clients to develop company brands, both copy & design.
- Pursued & established cross-promotional campaigns with local businesses.

January 2008 -September 2010

FREELANCE

Web Developer | Austin, TX

- EcoRise Youth Innovations: Worked closely with founder to develop & maintain PHP website. Pro bono.
- The Hub Cyclery: WordPress installation with a custom theme. Designed, built & maintained.

EDUCATION

Graduated July 2015

GENERAL ASSEMBLY

Web Development Immersive | Austin, TX

University of Texas Graduated August 2014

B.A. English, Minor in Film | Austin, TX

SKILLS

LANGUAGES

Ruby, JavaScript, SQL, HTML5, CSS3, SASS, JSON, XML, Bash

Frameworks + Libraries

Ruby on Rails, NodeJS, ¡Query, AJAX, BackboneJS, Sinatra, Bootstrap, Highcharts, Wordpress, Drupal, D3

METHODOLOGIES

Agile Development, MVC Design Patterns, Responsive Design, Object-Oriented Programming, Search Engine Optimization, Test-Driven Development

OTHER TOOLS

Git, GitHub, Heroku, PostgreSQL, MongoDB, Grunt, Bower, cPanel, Chrome DevTools, Adobe Creative Suite, MailChimp, QuickBooks

INTERESTS

- Web Development
- Filmmaking
- Travel
- Literature
- Cooking

FUN FACTS

- I have a working proficiency with Chinese & Spanish.
- Last year I took a solo trip abroad, backpacking across Japan & South Korea.
- I once watched all three Lord of the Rings films back-to-back...the extended editions.
- My favorite fruit is mangosteen.
- I can juggle.